

Florin Balint

Software Engineer
Technical software engine

Technical software engineering professional with more than 6 years of experience. Interested in solving difficult challenges and growing or learning as result of them.

Focused on designing, developing and maintaining quality software through proven development processes.

Email
florin.balint93@gmail.com
Address
Untermoosstrasse 1, 8047 Zürich
Phone
(+40) 746155622
Date of birth
Feb 25, 1993
Nationality

Romanian

Experience

Zürich, Switzerland Feb 2019 - Present Software Engineer

Google Switzerland GmbH

- Worked as an infrastructure developer, working on a development and production platform for developing applications and running them in GCP, using the Google Kubernetes Engine.
- Developed software in Go, Java and a proprietary Python derived configuration language.
- Created an automated workflow to productionize new servers.

Cluj Napoca, Romania Aug 2015 - Dec 2018 Software Developer

Tora Trading Services

- Programming a using Java based tech stack.
- Working on a high frequency trading data distribution application. Brought down the latency from 7µs to 3µs for processing an order.
- Integrating an old 32 bit VB API through Java COM (Windows) bridges.
- Implementing smart limits for traders using the company's OEMS (Order Execution Management System).

Cluj-Napoca, Romania Oct 2017 - Jan 2019 Teaching Assistant

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Conducted and taught students the *Object Oriented Programming* and *Fundamental Algorithms* laboratory classes.

Education

Cluj-Napoca, Romania Oct 2016 - Jul 2018 Master Degree in Computer Networking and Distributed Systems

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Master thesis: High performance concurrent data structures.

Cluj-Napoca, Romania Oct 2012 - Jul 2016 Computer Engineering

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Thesis: Clique based social graph clustering

Skills

Go

Java

Python

SQL

Linux

Bash

Kubernetes

Google Cloud Platform

Git

Angular

Languages

Romanian

Native

English Advanced